# **MARCIO MOREIRA JUNIOR**

# Linux SysAdmin | IT Infrastructure Specialist | DevOps Engineer | SRE | Cloud Engineer

**Location:** Sorocaba/SP/Brazil **Phone:** +55 (15) 99885-4030

E-mail: iam@marciomoreirajunior.com.br

## SUMMARY

IT professional with 25 years of experience, my first challenge was on the beginning of the century (2001) as a Linux Systems Administrator and have been developed my technical skills over the years, focused on specializing in network infrastructure, cybersecurity, and unix based operating systems.

I am 43 years old and have been deeply involved with Linux and FreeBSD since 1998, which sparked my passion for technology. Since 2001, I have worked consistently in the IT industry, gaining extensive experience in implementing, maintaining, and supporting users of all levels, complex networks and sensitive data systems. My career has been focused on ensuring high reliability and productivity in IT environments, with a strong emphasis on automation, containerization, cloud computing, and cybersecurity. Turned proficient in a bunch of technologies including Ansible, Terraform, LXD containers, NAS, Docker, Kubernetes, Shell Scripting, Python Scripting, Public Cloud providers, among others, and have successfully contributed to teams in Brazilian and international companies.

I also work in personal projects, like this blog (still in development), where I share my knowledge and experiences with the community and some scripts that i developed to make my daily basis work easier. I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow in my career.

### **TECH SKILLS**

Automation: Ansible, AWX, Chef, Puppet, Rundeck, Semaphore, Terraform;

CI/CD: BitBucket, Gitlab, Github, Gitea, Jenkins;

Cloud Computing: Azure, AWS, Digital Ocean, GCP, OpenStack, Oracle Cloud, Linode, Vultr;

Communication: Mailcow, RocketChat, SoGO;

Containers: LXD, Docker, Podman, Portainer, Kubernetes;
Databases: MariaDB, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis;
Development: Shell Script, Git, Go, HTML5, NodeJS, PHP, Python;

Management: Cockpit, Netbox, NextCloud, OpenProject, Sonatype Nexus, Virtualmin, Webmin;

Observability: Datadog, Elastic Search, Grafana, Icinga, Kibana, LogStash, Nagios, New Relic, Prometheus, Zabbix;

Network: Cisco routers, CloudFlare, Fortinet Appliances, Huawei routers, OpnSense, pfSense;

**Operating Systems:** Linux (Debian, Red Hat, Ubuntu), Unix (FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Solaris), Windows and MacOSX; **Security:** BackRest, FreeIPA, OpenLDAP, OpenVPN, RClone, Restic, Sophos, VaultWarden, Wazuh, WireGuard;

Storage: Ceph, GlusterFS;

Virtualization: Oracle VirtualBox, oVirt, Packer, Proxmox, QEMU, Vagrant, VMWare ESXi, VCenter;

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Mobi2Buy - Rio de Janeiro/Brazil (October 2024 / Present)

## **DevOps Engineer**

Responsible for managing servers, deploying applications, and maintaining cloud infrastructure on public providers. I worked on implementing CI/CD pipelines and automated server provisioning. Managed Kubernetes and Docker Swarm clusters for container orchestration.

- Server's Management;
- CI/CD pipelines;
- Server Deployment;
- Cloud Administration;
- Container orchestration;
- Monitoring;

**Tech Stack:** LINUX (DEBIAN, UBUNTU), UNIX (OPENBSD), DOCKER, DOCKER SWARM, PORTAINER, KUBERNETES, GIT, GITHUB ACTIONS, VMWARE ESXI, AWS, AZURE, ZABBIX, UPTIME KUMA, NEW RELIC.

# WiLine Networks – San Francisco/USA ( July 2022 to July 2024)

#### Senior SysOps Engineer

Managed infrastructure automation, provisioning LXD host nodes and CI/CD pipelines. Developed Bash scripts to streamline workflows and jobs automation. Administered multi-cloud environments and storage solutions. Ensured Observability while supporting Development, Networking, and Security teams.

- Server's Infrastructure Management;
- Deployment of Servers Host nodes for Containers;
- Python programming to automate tasks;
- Develop, maintain and update Ansible playbooks;
- CI/CD pipelines creation;
- Support for Development, Networking and Security teams;
- Cloud Computing administration;
- Storage administration;
- Backup administration;
- Container orchestration;

**Tech Stack:** LINUX (DEBIAN, UBUNTU, CENTOS, RED HAT), OPNSENSE, PFSENSE, NETBOX, PROMETEUS, GRAFANA, ANSI-BLE, TERRAFORM, DOCKER, LXD, JIRA, CONFLUENCE, ZABBIX, SHELL SCRIPT, PYTHON, RUNDECK, AWX, GITLAB, FLUENTD, VULTR, GCP, AWS, GLUSTERFS, CEPH, BACKUPPC, ZFS-AUTOBACKUP, PROXMOX. KUBERNETES, PORTAINER.

### Oi SA - São Paulo/Brazil (June 2020 to June 2022)

#### Senior System Administrator

Administered Linux and Unix environments, automated server provisioning, and maintained playbooks for infrastructure as code. Managed user's authentication, optimized public cloud operations, and handled network storage for unix servers. Deployed and monitored containerized applications.

- Server's Administration;
- Develop, maintain and update Ansible playbooks;
- · Cloud Computing administration;
- LDAP Administration:
- Operating system troubleshooting;
- Server's provisioning;
- Container orchestration;
- Storage Administration;

**Tech Stack:** LINUX (DEBIAN, UBUNTU, RED HAT, CENTOS), UNIX (AIX, SOLARIS, HP-UX), TERRAFORM, ANSIBLE, AWX, OPENLDAP, AWS, GCP, AZURE, FREEIPA, DOCKER, VERITAS INFOSCALE, SHELL SCRIPT, PYTHON, GITLAB, JENKINS, VMWARE ESXI.

# Computouch INC - Tulsa - Oklahoma/USA ( December 2014 to March 2020)

### Senior Infrastructure Analyst

Designed and implemented network architectures while managing Windows and Linux servers. Maintained backup solutions and optimized network storage management. Led security design and management, ensuring infrastructure resilience and data integrity.

- Network Design;
- Servers administration and provisioning (Windows Server, Linux Red Hat);
- Backup Management;
- Storage Management;
- Security Design and Management;

Tech Stack: LINUX (DEBIAN, CENTOS, RED HAT), WINDOWS (SERVER AND DESKTOP), MACOSX, CISCO ROUTERS, POSTFIX, LDAP, PYTHON, SHELL SCRIPT, TRUENAS, OPNSENSE, CISCO ROUTERS.

# Previous experience upon request.

# EDUCATION | COURSES | IDIOMS

- Graduated in Computer Networks Faculdade IBTA Sorocaba/SP (2004-2008)
- Masters in Applied Computing Univali Itajai/SC (2012-2014)
- Advanced in English, intermediate Spanish, basic Italian (Work in development);
- Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA Impacta/São Paulo SP (2001)
- Red Hat Fast Track for RHCE Red Hat/São Paulo SP (2010)